Guide to the Stanford University, Ninth Presidential Search Committee, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Ninth Presidential Search Committee, records
1991-1992
SC1143
Stanford University. Ninth Presidential Search Committee.
2 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Records from the Stanford University Ninth Presidential Search Committee, including notes on candidates, reports on the search process, and financial documents.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, 2000.
Information about Access
Materials in the collection are restricted. Contact the University Archivist for more information.
Biographical/Historical note
The Presidential Search Committee for Stanford's ninth president was appointed by the Board of Trustees in October 1991. Its charge was to make a recommendation to the Board for a successor to Donald Kennedy, Stanford's eighth president. In March 1992, Gerhard Casper, provost at the University of Chicago, was announced as Stanford's ninth president.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains records from the Stanford University Ninth Presidential Search Committee, including notes on candidates, reports on the search process, and financial documents.
Access Terms
Casper, Gerhard
Collection Contents
- Search committee binder, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Presidential Selection, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Archival report, Search for Stanford's Ninth President, 1992 Sep (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Casper, Gerhard, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Nominations (Box 1, Folder 8)
- JHF ranking, 1992 Jan 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- unlabeled (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Search criteria, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Notes re possible candidates, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Interview notes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
- Interviews, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Search Committee expenses, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 18-30)
- Report compiled for archives, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- News clippings and press releases, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)